Speier, Hans; Papers ger084
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence files, 1911-1988; 3; 378 folders
  - Correspondence with co-editors (Harold Lasswell and Daniel Lerner) and contributors to Propaganda and Communication in World History, 1968-1983; 3.269
    - Gombrich, E. H., 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 57)
    - Halman, Talat S., 1971-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 58)
    - Inkeles, Alex, 1971; 1974 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 59)
    - Isaacs, Harold R., 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 60)
    - Janowitz, Morris, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 61)
    - Killian, Lewis, 1972-1975 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 62)
    - Kirk, George, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 63)
    - Landes, David, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 64)
    - Lasswell, Harold D., 1938-1978 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 65)
    - Lerner, Daniel, 1947-1982 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 66)
    - Lewis, Bernard, 1970-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 67)
    - Lewy, Günter, 1972-1980 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 68)
    - Ludz, Peter C., 1969-1979 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 69)
    - Mardin, Serif, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 70)
    - Martin, L. John, 1970-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 71)
    - McGowan, Bruce, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 72)
    - McKeon, Richard, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 73)
    - Mead, Margaret, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 74)
    - Momigliano, A. D., 1970-1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 75)
    - Morse, Richard, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 76)
    - Nelson, Benjamin, 1970; 1975 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 77)
    - Nisbet, Robert, 1968-1977 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 78)
    - Oppenheim, Adolf Leo, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 79)
    - Padover, Saul K., 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 80)
    - Passin, Herbert, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 81)
    - Posener, Georges, 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 82)
    - Pye, Lucien, 1973 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 83)
    - Rogow, Arnold A., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 84)
    - Rolle, Andrew, 1969-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 85)
    - Rosten, Leo C., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 86)
    - Schachter, Oscar, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 87)
    - Schramm, Wilbur, 1973-1974 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 88)
    - Segal, Seymour, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 89)
    - Sharma, R. S., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 90)
    - Spengler, Joseph J., 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 91)
    - Thapar, Romila, 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 92)
    - Tyler, Ralph W., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 93)
    - von Grunebaum, Gustave E., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 94)
    - Werblowski, Z. J. R., 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 95)
    - Wiesner, Jerome B., 1973 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 96)
    - Wright, Arthur F., 1971-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 97)
    - The University Press of Hawaii, 1975-1983 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 98)
  - Thyssen-Workshop "Probleme der Regierbarkeit" correspondence and papers, 1974-1976; 3.270
    - Baring, Arnulf, 1974-1975 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 99)
    - Brand, Gerd, 1966-1978 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 100)
    - Hennis, William, 1971-1988 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 101)
    - Höllerer, W., 1975 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 102)
    - Kielmansegg, Peter Graf, 1976 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 103)
    - Matz, Ulrich, 1976-1977 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 104)
    - Schieder, Theodor, 1976 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 105)
    - Workshop schedule, notes, Undated (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 106)
    - Baring, Arnulf, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 107)
    - Görtemaker, Manfred. "Systematisches Protokoll des Workshop 'Regierbarkeit und Entwicklungsfähigkeit der Bundesrepublik Deutschland'", Undated (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 108)
    - Johnson, Nevil. "Studien zur Regierbarkeit der westlichen Demokratien", Undated (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 109)
    - Kielmannsegg, Peter Graf/Ulrich Matz. "Politiksteuerung durch allgemeine Wahlen als Legitimationsproblem", Undated (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 110)
  - Pikart, Eberhard. "Historische Überlegungen zum Phänomen der Krise", Undated (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 111)
  - Schieder, Theodor. "Einmaligkeit oder Wiederkehr", Undated (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 112)
- Manuscripts and typescripts, ca. 1920-1987; 4
  This series is divided into two sub-series: 1) typescripts of books written or edited by Speier; and 2) typescripts and manuscripts of shorter writings, including early stories and poems, and essayistic writings.
  - Typescripts of books written or edited by H. Speier, 4.1; 60 file folders
    Typescripts and notes for Speier's work Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus (English: The German White Collar Workers and Hitler) make up the largest part of this sub-series. Also included in this section are reviews of many of Speier's publications.
    Arranged by title of work.
    - The Salaried Employee in German Society, 1939; mimeographed typescript (Box 5 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 113)
    - Divided Berlin. "Additions to the American edition", 1962 (Box 5 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 114)
    - Witz und Politik, 1975 (Box 5 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 115)
      Typescripts with numerous correspondence.
    - Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus, Undated; 4.1.4; typescripts and notes cubic ft.
      - Parts I-IV, typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 1)
      - Parts V-X, typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 2)
      - Chapters I-V (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 3)
        Typescripts with correspondence, handwritten notes.
      - Chapters VI-X. Handwritten notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 4)
      - Chapters XI-XIV. Handwritten notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 5)
      - Chapters I, II, typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 6)
      - Chapters VI-XI, typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 7)
      - Chapters XII-XIV, typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 8)
      - Pp. 1-141 (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 9-10)
        Typescript with correspondence; photocopies.
      - Pp. 142-262 (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 11-12)
      - Pp. 263-330 (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 13-14)
      - Page proofs (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 15)
      - "Vorwort", typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 16)
      - "Einleitung", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 17)
      - Chap. 1: "Die Vielfalt der Angestellten", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 18)
      - Chap. 2: "Die soziale Herkunft der Angestellten", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 19)
      - Chap. 3: "Der Aufstieg im Beruf", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 20)
      - Chap. 4: "Die Schichtung nach Tätigkeitsgruppen", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 21)
      - Chap. 5: "Angestellte und Arbeiter -- Angestellte und Unternehmer", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 22)
      - Chap. 6: "Mittelständische Auffassungen und Klassentheorie", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 23)
      - Chap. 7: "Die Grundlagen der sozialen Geltung", typescript, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 24)
      - Chap. 8: "Die Betriebshierarchie und der Fetischcharakter des Vorgesetzten", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 25)
      - Chap. 9: "Die Funktion der Bildung", typescripts (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 26)
      - Chap. 10: "Die nationale Gesinnung", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 27)
      - Chap. 11: "Die Verbände bis zum Ende des Kaiserreichs", typescript (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 28)
      - Chap. 12: "Die Vergewerkschaftung zu Beginn der Weimarer Republik, typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 29)
      - Chap. 13: "Die Verbände gegen Ende der Weimarer Republik", typescript (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 30)
      - Chap. 14: "Der Verfall der Verbände", typescripts, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 31)
      - "Anhang A", typescript, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 32)
      - "Anhang B", typescript (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 33)
      - Miscellaneous early versions, notes (Box 6 (4.1.4-Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus), Folder 34)
    - The German White Collar Workers and Hitler. English translation of Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus, Undated; 4.1.5; typescripts cubic ft.
      - Chapter X: "Nationalism of White Collar Workers in the Weimar Republic", mimeograph (Box 6 (4.1.5-The German White Collar Workers and Hitler), Folder 35)
      - Pages 1-162, final typescript (Box 6 (4.1.5-The German White Collar Workers and Hitler), Folder 36)
      - Pages 163-323, final typescript (Box 6 (4.1.5-The German White Collar Workers and Hitler), Folder 37)
      - Notes to chapters (Box 6 (4.1.5-The German White Collar Workers and Hitler), Folder 38)
    - "Emil Lederer, 1882-1939: Personal Reminiscences", 1977; typescript, notes (Box 7 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 1)
    - "Emil Lederer (1882-1939): Life and Work", Undated; typescripts, photocopies (Box 7 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 2)
    - "Emil Lederer (1882-1939): Leben und Werk", Undated (Box 7 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 3)
      Typescripts and notes of German version.
    - Propaganda and Communication in World History, Outlines, 1979-1980 (Box 7 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 4)
    - Propaganda and Communication in World History. Editor's introduction: "The Symbolic Instrument", Undated; mimeographed (Box 7 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 5)
    - Propaganda and Communication in World History. Miscellaneous materials, Undated (Box 7 (4-Manuscripts and typescripts), Folder 6)
    - Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier, Undated; 4.1.12
      - Reviews of essayistic writings (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 7)
      - Mayer, Carl. "A Note on H. Speier's 'Social Stratification and Democracy'" (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 8)
      - War in Our Time, 1939 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 9)
        Review.
      - German Radio Propaganda, 1944 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 10)
      - Social Order and the Risks of War: Papers in Political Sociology, 1952; 1969 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 11)
      - German Rearmament and Atomic War, 1957 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 12)
      - Divided Berlin, 1961 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 13)
      - Force and Folly: Essays on Foreign Affairs, 1969 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 14)
      - Witz und Politik, 1975 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 15)
      - Die Angestellten vor dem Nationalsozialismus, 1977 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 16)
      - German White Collar Workers and the Rise of Hitler (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 17)
      - Propaganda and Communication in World History, 1979-1980 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 18)
      - From the Ashes of Disgrace, 1981 (Box 7 (4.1.12-Reviews of writings or edited works by Hans Speier), Folder 19)
  - Typescripts and manuscripts of early unpublished poems and short stories, published and unpublished essayistic writings, 1920-1987; 4.2; 160 file folders
    This series is arranged into three sections: the first contains Speier's early writings, including poetry, aphorisms and short stories from the 1920s and 1930s. The largest section is made up of Speier's essayistic writings and contains a number of pieces written during the 1940s when Speier was employed by the Office of War Information and the Department of State. The last section contains Speier's book reviews.
    - Early unpublished writings, ca. 1922-1939; 4.2.1
      - Poems, 1922-1925 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 20)
      - Poems, 1930s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 21)
      - Aphorisms, 1930s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 22)
      - Untitled short sketches, 1920s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 23)
      - "Die Bruecke. Eine nuchterne Novelle", 1920s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 24)
      - "Gegen Morgen". Short story, 1920s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 25)
      - "Meditation und Maske". Short story, 1920s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 26)
      - "Schubach". Short story, 1920s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 27)
      - "Der Kranke. Skizze". Short story, 1920s (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 28)
      - "Anton Luber. Novelle". Short story, 1923 September (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 29)
      - "Die drei Begegnungen mit dem Herrn Nikolaus Janzetti. Novelle", ca. 1925 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 30)
      - "Der Neunzehnjaehrige. Erzählung", dated 1925 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 31)
      - "Stimmen durcheinander. Roman", ca. 1925 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 32)
      - "Aus einem Brief des Herrn M. (statt einer Vorrede)", ca. 1925 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 33)
        Typescript of a novel.
      - "Eine wahre Begebenheit. An Franz Kafka erinnernd" Sketch, ca. 1938 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 34)
      - "Fahrt ueber den Ozean". Sketch, ca. 1938 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 35)
      - "In der Nacht zum 3. Februar 1938" (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 36)
      - "Aus einem Gespraech in New Hampshire, Sommer 1938" (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 37)
      - "Traum", ca. 1938-1939 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 38)
      - Untitled sketch, 1938 December 15 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 39)
      - "Brief an Sybille bei ihrer Ankunft in America", ca. 1938 (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 40)
      - "New Hampshire 1939" (Box 7 (4.2.1-Early unpublished writings), Folder 41)
    - Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier, texts of speeches, undated; 4.2.2
      - "Notes on German nationalism" (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 42)
      - "Morale policy in Total War" (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 43)
      - Essay on population, ca. 1927-1928 (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 44)
      - "How Not to be Blackmailed in the Nuclear Age. The Impact of Technology on Dipolomacy" (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 45)
      - "The Sociology of Freedom. A Study in Alfred Webers Sociology of Universal History" (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 46)
      - Transcript of H. Speier Speech in San Francisco" (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 47)
      - Speech text on political language (Box 7 (4.2.2-Essayistic writings presumably authored by Speier,), Folder 48)
    - Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically, Undated; 4.2.3
      - "Der Dichter Ernst Barlach", 1925; clipping (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 49)
      - "Alfred Weber. Zu seinem 60. Geburtstage", 1928 July 28; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 50)
      - "Entstehung und Geschichte des modernen Buergertums. Zwei Vorträge auf der Deutschen Welle", 1928 November; typescripts (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 51)
      - "Die Geschichtsphilosophie Lassalles. I & II", 1929; reprints (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 52)
      - "Lassalles Nachlass", 1929; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 53)
      - "Zur Soziologie der bürgerlichen Intelligenz in Deutschland", 1929; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 54)
      - "Tolstoi im Spiegel des Marxismus", 1930; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 55)
      - "Emil Lederer zum fünfzigsten Geburtstag", ca. 1930; typescripts (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 56)
      - "Sociology or Ideology? Notes on the Sociology of the Intelligentsia", 1930; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 57)
      - "Ideologie und Utopie. Karl Mannheims soziologisches Werk", 1930 February 13 (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 58)
        Notes, clipping.
      - "Soziologie oder Ideologie", 1930 April; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 59)
      - "Die Intellektuellen in der Theorie des Marxismus", 1930 November; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 60)
      - "Die Intellektuellen und ihr sozialer Beruf", 1930 December; typescript, reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 61)
      - "Die Soziologie des Wissens", 1930 December 28; clipping (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 62)
      - "Marx und Engels über die Brechung der Zinsknechtschaft", 1931; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 63)
      - "Marx und Engels als Freunde", ca. 1930; mimeographed typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 64)
      - "Marx and Engels as Friends", ca. 1930-1932; mimeographed typescripts (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 65)
      - "Schöpferische Freundschaften. IV. Marx und Engels", ca. 1931; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 66)
      - "Politik als Wissenschaft", ca. 1931; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 67)
      - "Sozialer Liberalismus?", ca. 1931; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 68)
      - "Verbürgerlichung des Proletariats?", 1931 March 27; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 69)
      - "Erwerbslosigkeit und Politik", ca. 1931/1932; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 70)
      - "Rudolf Goldscheid", 60th birthday, 1932; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 71)
      - "Zum Problem des Reformismus", 1932 May; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 72)
      - "Das Proletariat und seine Kritiker", 1932 September; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 73)
      - "Marx als Soziologe", 1933; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 74)
      - "On the German Sociology of Understanding", dated Spring 1934; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 75)
      - "Social Stratification in the Urban Community", 1936 April; clipping (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 76)
      - "The Social Condition of the Intellectual in Exile" / "Die soziale Lage der Intellektuellen im Exil", 1937 September; typescripts (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 77)
      - "Class Structure and 'Total War'", 1939 June; reprint (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 78)
      - "Comment on the Research Project on Peace", 1939 October 26; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 79)
      - "Research Programme to be undertaken under the auspices of the Graduate Faculty of Political and Social Science at the New School for Social Research" (with Ernst Kris), ca. 1940; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 80)
      - "Memorandum on a Research Project 'The Social Readjustment of Military Officers in Case of Disarmament", 1940 April 23; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 81)
      - "Comment on the Research Project on Peace", 1940 April 25; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 82)
      - "Risiko, Sicherheit und moderne Heldenverehrung", 1940 December; typescripts (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 83)
      - "Notes on Risk, Security and Heroism", 1941 March; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 84)
      - "Wissenssoziologie", ca. 1941; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 85)
      - "Notes on the Stab-in-the-Back Doctrine", 1941 March 5; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 86)
      - "Re: Arms Communiques", 1941 July 10; typescript (Box 7 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 87)
      - "Notes on Analysis of Warfiles", 1941 July 27; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 1)
      - "Shakespeares Der Sturm", 1942; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 2)
      - "American Propaganda to Germany", 1942 December 14; typescript (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 3)
      - "Ludendorff: The German Concept of Total War", 1943; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 4)
      - "Nazi Propaganda and Its Decline", 1943; reprint (Box 8 (4.2.3-Essayistic writings, arranged chronologically), Folder 5)